ハァ…。
I see our roles have been reversed.
うっわ！
Very well.
うわ！
Here I go!
ハァハァ…。
Awesome!
目覚めましたか？ ここは？
Ready, and...
最終試験会場横の控室です。
They shattered my record with ease.
よっこいしょっと。
How much have they improved
in such a short period of time?
そっか ハンター試験の最中だったんだ
I am impressed. Although you still fall a bit
short of my full height.
腕は　すぐに　くっつきますよ。
Okay! Let's go again!
非常に　きれいに 折ってくれています。
No way.
むしろ　完治した後には 丈夫になるくらいのもんです。
You won't stop until you win. One more time... Just once more! Oh, you passed.
何はともあれ 合格おめでとうございます。
Nice jump. Sorry... They're only kids, so let it slide.
サトツさん　俺…。
But it comes down to figuring out
who to assign to which sport.
ダメです。 あっ。
Do we know all the sports they'll use?
不合格者が何を言っても 合格できないのと同じく
We've managed to confirm these eight. Beach Volleyball
Wrestling
Boxing
Juggling
Free Throws
Sumo
Bowling
Ping Pong
合格した者を 不合格にすることもできません。
Depending on our success,
they may add additional sports. I understand... Hey, this is bad!
あとは　君次第ですよ。
What is it?
自分にプロの資格がないと 判断したなら
Team Genthru is up to ninety-seven cards.
ライセンスカードを処分するのも 封印するのも自由です。
Then they're only missing...
売却するのもいいでしょう どうせ他人には使用不可です。
Patch of Shore and Lucky Alexandrite!
一度合格した者が 再び試験を受けることは
Over the past week, we've run various simulations and have prepared accordingly.
できませんがね。 先人達の偉業のかいもあり
Given Team Genthru's current situation, we can't afford to lose.
プロのハンターは かなり優遇されています。
We have to win! Yes, we'll win.
試験を受けに来るやからも 後を絶ちません。
This isn't too bad...
そんな連中さえいなければ
Okay, let's go.
ほとんどの プロのハンターにとって
I'll send you packing.
このカードは　命より 大事なものであると同時に
His special ability is teleportation.
意味のないガラクタ同然の ものでもあるのです。
He can teleport his uppercut.
大事なのは
Fight!
「ハンターになってから 何をなしたか」ですよ。
H-He's fast! An infighter?
「何をなしたか」？
If I'm close enough, his Emitter
advantages are worthless.
ゴンくん このカードを使う時期は 自分で決めればいい。
He'll be so busy guarding, he won't have a chance to use teleportation!
君なら　それができるでしょう。
Nice!
うん！　これまで いろんな人に助けてもらって
Suggesting that he can only teleport while standing within the ring.
いっぱい　借りも　つくったしね。 それを全部　返してから 使うことにするよ。
Essentially, he's revealing that
he isn't all that strong.
では　あらためて 合格おめでとうございます。
An opponent unworthy of us.
ありがとう　サトツさん。
The winner is Barry! Yes!
他の人は　どうなったの？ まだ　試験の最中でしょ？
The winner is Rodriot!
いえ　試験は終了しました。
The winner is Kess!
本当に？
Yes!
ええ　君は　ほぼ丸一日 寝ていたんですよ。
That's three wins!
そうだったの？ 他の合格者は 簡単な講習を受けています。
In terms of combat strength, those six are very strong.
後で　君にも受けてもらいますが。
This is getting interesting...
誰が落ちたの？
You guys can toss your matches.
それは…。
I'll take it from here.
キルア氏です。
Roger that. Wait!
キルアが…　何で？
I'm done following your orders. I'll be doing things my own way now.
その前に　君が気を失った後から 順を追ってお話ししましょう。
Hey, brat! Let's step outside! Outside? Do you think this is a sumo ring?
そのほうが理解しやすいと 思いますから。
I'm done playing around. Want me to kill you here?
うん。
Hey, Bobobo!
君が気を失った後…。
That's a violation of our agreement. Want to go back to the slammer, Bobobo?
そいつが目覚めたら きっと合格は辞退するぜ。
I'm done playing this stupid game! Anyone else with me?
確かに　ゴンの性格なら そう言うだろう。 不合格者は　たった１人なんだろ？
If we team up, we can crush that bastard. And then we can use a ship
to get off this island!
心配無用　ゴンは合格じゃ。
You'll be punished for breaking the taboo.
本人が何と言おうと それは変わらんよ。
Didn't I warn you?
はぁ…。 はぁ…。
Y-Yes, you did...
仮に　ゴンが　ごねて わしを殺したとしても 合格した後で 資格が取り消されることはない。
Did that idiot think I wouldn't kill him?
なるほどな。
Okay, I'll go next.
わざと？
We'll be doing the fighting.
ゴンを殺さずに 「参った」と言わせるぐらい 心得てるはずだろ？ あんたならさ。
We explained how this works. If the nine of us cannot secure eight victories, you can just forfeit without fighting.
俺は誰かを拷問する時は
Yeah, don't worry.
一生　恨まれることを 覚悟して　やる。
That guy has a much stronger aura than the rest.
どんな奴でも　痛めつけられた 相手を見る目には
And judging by the previous conversation, he must be a Game Master.
負の光が宿るもんだ。
Can I ask something?
目に映る憎しみや 恨みの光ってのは
That guy's dead. What about the sumo match?
訓練しても なかなか隠せるもんじゃ　ねえ。
Hmm? Oh, you get the win.
しかし　ゴンの目には それが　なかった。
But we never decided who we were sending.
信じられるか？ 腕を折られた直後なのによ。
You're the one who said you
were going to do the sumo.
あいつの目は　もう　そのことを 忘れちまってるんだぜ。
I don't care who you give the win to. Just give it to one of the guys
standing in the back.
要は　気に入っちまったんだ あいつが。
Okay, you get the sumo win.
ふん…。
Eh? Wait, me?
あえて敗因を挙げるなら そんなとこだ。
That gives us four wins.
その後　すぐに 第２試合が始まりました。
Pick the eight members you'll field.
始め！
I already have mine.
うぅ！
Yes, one win per person.
ハッ。
So the victorious team receives eight wins.
なっ…！ フフっ。
Simple enough, yes? So that was the plan?
僕の負けだ。 えっ？
we defeat, he can still win
the entire game alone.
こうして クラピカ氏が勝ちました。
Razor and the fourteen devils...
ヒソカは何を…。
The devils are his Nen ability!
分かりません
I'm against this...
とにかくヒソカ氏は 自ら　負けを宣言しました。
If we have to field eight, you need two more!
第３試合は ハンゾー氏とポックル氏。
I'm not fighting that guy! I'm leaving now...
ゴンくんの時と 同じような体勢になりましたが
Once the match begins, you can deliberately let yourself be hit—
あっさり　ポックル氏が 負けを認めました。
Screw that! Didn't you see that?
悪いが　あんたにゃ遠慮しねえぜ。
If he hits us with that ball, we're dead! Oh, just so everything is clear,
we'll be using a normal ball.
第４試合は　ヒソカ氏とボドロ氏。
But with Nen, it's just as strong as
the Nen projectile I launched earlier.
はぁ！
This is crazy... I'm outta here!
ふんっ　オリャ！　うお！
Sorry, but I don't want to die yet...
はぁ！
H-Hold on! We'll think of something real quick.
なかなか ボドロ氏は諦めませんでした。
So we're forced to pick two
of these spineless wimps. We'll do this by ourselves.
ヒソカ氏が 何か耳打ちした　その直後
Do you have a problem if we only field six? Yes, actually, I can't let you do that...
今度は ボドロ氏が負けを宣言しました。
You will have to field eight members.
第５試合のキルア氏と ポックル氏は 開始と同時に キルア氏が戦線離脱。
Otherwise, why ask you to recruit fifteen?
悪いけど　あんたとは 戦う気がしないんでね。 恐らく　次で勝てると 判断してたんでしょう。
Saying this to an in-game character
is probably pointless, but wasn't Bobobo one of your allies?
しかし　第６試合
What did he do to deserve death?
レオリオ氏が　ボドロ氏の ケガを理由に延期を要求し
Burglary-murder and rape-murder. Eleven confirmed counts alone.
先にキルア氏とギタラクル氏が 戦うことになりました。
This is the real world.
始め！
This place, Greed Island, is located
somewhere in the real world.
キルア氏にとって 最大の誤算が　そこにありました。
This game takes place in the real world.
久しぶりだね　キル。
This guy, Razor, is a Game Master, a real human.
カタカタカタ…
Game Master? One of the people who made this game.
ハッ。
I never noticed.
兄貴…。
Since this island is still isolated
from the rest of the world.
えっ　ギタラクルって キルアの兄さんだったの？ ええ　イルミという名前のね。
Yeah. I was instructed not to go easy on you by your old man.
キルアの兄貴？ 鍼で顔を変えていたのか！
I've had enough... I don't wanna die! Count me out! I'm gone!
母さんとミルキを 刺したんだって？
It's okay, let them leave. But then we can't have a match!
まぁね。 母さん　泣いてたよ。
I'll count as three.
息子に そんな　ひどい目に遭わされちゃ。 感激してた。
You're doing the same thing, so it shouldn't be a problem.
えぇ!?
Yeah, that's fine.
「あの子が立派に成長してくれて 嬉しい」ってさ。
Now it's eight-on-eight.
でも　やっぱり外に出すのは 心配だからって
I'll explain the rules.
それとなく様子を見て来るように 頼まれたんだけど　奇遇だね。
The game starts with one outside
player and seven inside.
まさか　キルがハンターに なりたいと思ってたなんてね。
The first team to run out of inside players loses.
実は俺も　次の仕事の関係上 資格をとりたくてさ。
Any player inside the court who's hit by
a ball thrown by an opponent is out, and must move outside.
別に　なりたかったわけじゃ ないよ。
However, you may bring one player inside
the court again by saying "Back."
ただ　何となく受けてみただけさ。 そうか…　安心したよ。
And if the ball hits an area outside
the court, without any players, the opposing team gets the ball.
心置きなく　忠告できる。
Now, the important stuff...
お前の天職は… 殺し屋なんだから。
The rules regarding hits
employ a cushion effect. For example, if I throw the ball
and it hits opposing player A, ricochets, and hits opposing player B
before hitting the floor, both A and B are out.
本当に　そう言ったの？ 話には聞いてたけど すごい　一家だなぁ。 さらに彼は続けました。 お前は熱を持たない　闇人形だ。
But if player B in that scenario
is able to catch the ball, player A is safe. Exactly. But if I throw the ball and it
hits opposing player A, ricochets, and hits my teammate, player C,
before hitting the floor, only player C is out.
自身は何も欲しがらず 何も望まない。 陰を糧に動くお前が 唯一　喜びを抱くのは
Then if player C catches the ball,
does that mean player A is out? Indeed. Uh...
人の死に触れた時。
Do you have a question?
お前は　親父と俺に そう育てられた。
If an outside player hits someone
with the ball, is the hit player out? Naturally, they're out. But only one player
そんな　お前が 何を求めてハンターになると？
can return to the court using Back.
確かに
I am Number 0, the ref.
ハンターには　なりたいと 思ってるわけじゃ　ない。
Let's have a clean game. We will now begin the game.
だけど　俺にだって 欲しいものぐらいある。
Ready...
ないね。 ある！ 今　望んでることだって　ある！ ふん。
Go!
言ってごらん　何が望みか。
You can make the first move.
違う！
You got him!
ゴンと…　友達になりたい。
Let's keep this up. There!
もう　人殺しなんて　うんざりだ。
Oh, this is easy. Okay, all ready to go...
ゴンと友達になって 普通に遊びたい。
Huh? What did you say? I'm prepared to defeat you now.
無理だね。
Heh, that's funny.
お前に友達なんか できっこないよ。
Show us what you've got!
そう　教え込まれたからね。
H-He stopped it with one hand?
今の　お前には ゴンが　まぶし過ぎて
Right, then... Time to launch the counterattack.
測りきれないでいるだけだ 友達になりたいわけじゃ　ない。
He's standing so far back...
違う…。
Is he going to pass it?
彼のそばにいれば　いつか お前は　彼を殺したくなるよ。
Fast!
殺せるか殺せないか 試したくなる。 なぜなら
Can I dodge it? No way! Can I catch it and live?
お前は根っからの 人殺しだから。
No! I'll die! Death White Goreinu!
キルア！ お前の兄貴か何だか知らねえが 言わせてもらうぜ！
Nice rebound.
いつもの調子で　さっさと ぶっ飛ばして　合格しちまえ！
Goreinu's outside the court! I see...
ゴンと友達になりたいだと!? 寝ぼけんな！
You have the ability to change
places with your Nen beasts.
とっくに　お前ら ダチ同士だろうがよ！
The Nen creature was shattered...
ハッ。 えっ？ 少なくとも ゴンは　そう思ってるはずだぜ！
This reflects what Goreinu imagined would
happen when he saw Razor's attack.
そうなの？ 当ったりめぇだ　バカ！ そうか　参ったな。
He immediately grasped the gap between
our opponent's strength and his own.
あっちは　もう 友達のつもりなのか…。
He won't easily rid himself of that image.
よし　ゴンを殺そう。
It'll be impossible for him to
recover during this match.
彼は　どこにいるの？ ちょっと待ってください まだ試合は…。
Yes, the exchange was performed
with Nen, so it broke no rules. However, Back must be used to
bring Goreinu inside the court. Damn... Is this how it ends?
隣の控室に…！
That pass is so fast!
ん？
I can't follow the ball!
俺が落ちて 自動的にキルが合格しちゃうね。
It's heavy...
あっ　いけない… それは　ゴンを殺っても一緒か。
As heavy as a bowling ball. This is gonna have insane power.
うん…　そうだ！ まず合格してからゴンを殺そう！
He focused his aura in his back,
and avoided a lethal blow.
テメェ…。
I-I'm fine... Don't touch me.
それなら仮に ここの全員を殺しても 俺の合格が取り消されることは ないよね？
If a player is unable to continue
playing, they're disqualified.
うむ　ルール上は問題ない。 聞いたかい？　キル。
They won't be allowed to play in or outside the court,
so keep that in mind.
俺と戦って　勝たないと ゴンを助けられない。
Are you okay? Yeah, I've really lost it... Damn, in overall combat ability, I should still be stronger than they are.
友達のために　俺と戦えるかい？ できないね　なぜなら お前は友達なんかより
But when it comes to the basics like
agility and reflexes, they have me beat.
今　この場で俺を倒せるか 倒せないかのほうが　大事だから。
It's been a while since I've
had to work really hard.
そして　もう お前の中で答えは出ている。 「俺の力では　兄貴を倒せない」と。
Maybe it's time to start training from scratch. I don't think I've done any basic
training in the past few years.
「勝ち目のない敵とは戦うな」
Ideally, we could knock out
everyone on the other team
俺が　口を酸っぱくして 教えたよね？
without giving up the ball. Hisoka...
動くな！ うっ。
Okay, give me the ball.
少しでも動いたら 戦闘開始の合図と見なす。 同じく　お前と俺の体が 触れた瞬間から戦闘開始とする。
Oh, that's right. If he uses his Bungee Gum, he can
retrieve the ball after it hits! Now, do try to entertain me.
止める方法は　一つだけ 分かるな？
Surely this isn't everything you have.
だが　忘れるな。
Okay, that's three down!
お前と俺が戦わなければ 大事なゴンが死ぬことになるよ。
With Back, the other team still has five players! With Bungee Gum, we can stay on the offensive.
やっちまえ　キルア！
All that's left is the order we target them.
どっちにしろ　お前もゴンも 殺させやしねえ！
Question for the ref. Can the last player inside the court
そいつは何があっても 俺達が止める！
use Back at the second he's hit?
お前の　やりたいようにしろ！
That's not allowed. For a moment, there would
be zero players in the court, so that team would lose.
参った…　俺の負けだよ。
at the instant that the last player is hit. Okay. Hisoka... Yes, I understand.
あぁ　よかった。 これで戦闘解除だね。
He throws a strong ball. Numbers 2, 6, and 7 can't catch it.
ハッハッハッ　ウソだよ　キル ゴンを殺すなんて　ウソさ。
Nice and strong!
お前を　ちょっと試してみたのだよ でも　これで　はっきりした。
If we're lucky, we can take out
6 and 7 at the same time!
お前に友達をつくる資格は　ない 必要も　ない。
Th-They combined?
今まで通り 親父や俺の言うことを聞いて
You're strong.
ただ仕事をこなしていれば それで　いい。
Is that allowed?! It is.
ハンター試験も 必要な時期が来れば俺が指示する。
If you're allowed to combine,
are you allowed to split?
今は必要ない。
Yes, but you cannot surpass the maximum
number of players on the court.
レオリオ氏やクラピカ氏が 何を言っても 反応さえしませんでした。
It's my turn to attack again. Now we have to retake the ball again.
第６試合は レオリオ氏　対　ボドロ氏。
If we're going to stop his ball... Ken!
ボドロ氏が回復し 試合開始と同時でした。 始め！
Their Nen is smooth and quite beautiful.
ん？
They must have trained hard. But if Razor throws the ball at full strength, Ken won't be enough.
一瞬のことでした。 キルア氏はボドロ氏を 死に至らしめました。
Here I come, Gon!
委員会は 彼を不合格と見なしました。
Bring it!
ゴンくん？ みんな　どこにいるの？
It won't work! Run away!
まだ休んでなければ いけません　ゴンくん！
You'll die!
ゴン…。
Gon! Are you okay?! I'm just fine!
キルアに謝れ！
However, next time, I'll catch it!
自分と友達になりたいという キルアの素直な気持を 踏みにじり
Gon is now fired up.